# Abraham Murciano

Software Engineer

### Personal Information

Ha-Va'ad ha-Le'umi St 21 abrahammurciano@gmail.com Jerusalem +44~7397~842~936 Israel +972~54~286~1293

GitHub https://github.com/abrahammurciano

LinkedIn https://linkedin.com/in/abraham-murciano-402952143



#### About Me

Passionate software engineer, full stack web developer, and IT technician offering 6 years of programming, maintenance, troubleshooting and repair experience combined with an aptitude for quickly adopting new skills. Hardworking and thorough with a passion for learning and gaining more experience in this field.

## **Professional Experience**

2015–2018 | Full Stack Web Developer – Freelance

Designed sites to be compatible with top browsers, including Chrome, Firefox, and Safari, both on **desktop and mobile**.

Used various technologies, including object oriented programming, PHP, JavaScript, and SQL to obtain optimal performance in websites.

Created site layout and user interface using HTML and CSS practices.

Hands-on experience using **Linux** and Apache web servers.

Summer 2018 | Computer Technician – PC Clinic, Gibraltar

Built customised desktop computers.

Removed and replaced malfunctioning components to correct hardware problems.

Removed malware and other threats from laptops and desktop systems.

Demonstrated professionalism and courtesy with customers while working to resolve complaints, problems or respond to questions.

2019–2021 | Computer Science Tutor – Freelance

Taught less capable classmates and students from younger years material from various

courses.

Skills

Programming | C/C++, Python, C#, Java, PHP, JavaScript, SQL, Prolog, Bash, Agena, IATEX

UI Design HTML, CSS, WPF, XAML

Databases MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, SQLite

Other Linux

Education

2018-Present | BSc in Computer Science, Jerusalem College of Technology, Israel.

Expected October 2021. Current GPA 90.2%

2011–2017 | Gibraltar Boys Secondary School, Gibraltar.

# Notable Open Source Projects

Co-manged team of **eight** student volunteers.

Taught the less experienced team members to properly use Git.

Applied many **object oriented** principles. Applied many python programming **paradigms**.

Designed and created a  $\bf PosgreSQL$  database for the project.

https://github.com/DenverCoder1/jct-discord-bot

rey-trace | Created a ray-tracing graphics engine in Java.

Implemented a multi-threaded solution for optimal performance.

Practised working in an Agile environment.

https://github.com/abrahammurciano/rey-trace

Jack Compiler | Wrote a compiler for the educational object-based language Jack.

https://github.com/abrahammurciano/jack2hack Wrote an interpreter for the educational Turing-machine-like language S.

https://github.com/abrahammurciano/s-interpreter

## Languages

S Interpreter

English Fluent
Spanish Fluent
Hebrew Basic